## **ROQEEB OBADARA**

obadararoqeeb@gmail.com +2348141234141 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Oworonshoki, Lagos

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY:**

An expert web developer specializing in front end development, ambitious and self-motivated with a strong technical background that possesses self-discipline and the ability to work with the minimum of supervision, a good team player, who thrives on creating engaging creative solutions, deadline orientated and has the ability to produce detailed technical specifications from client requirements.

### **PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES**

- Ability to build customized websites to the highest specifications.
- Ability to work to under pressure and to tight deadlines.
- Ability to come up with solutions to seemingly intractable problems.
- Ability to carry out routine application maintenance.
- Ability to drive projects forward.
- Ability to work closely with other developers and professionals.
- Good communication skills.
- Ability to make recommendations on the use of new and emerging technologies.
- Ability to work through a project life cycle.
- Ability to maintain existing software applications & develop new ones.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Web Development
- WordPress (Divi)
- JavaScript
- HTML

- CSS
- React
- Git and Github
- Python

- Material Design
- Data Science
- API
- Database

#### **EXPERIENCES**

## NEWMEQ DIGITAL CONCEPTS, Ibadan 2021-Present Front-End Developer/Content Creator

- I build the front-end for all kinds of websites ranging from E-commerce, blog, events websites and business websites for clients.
- Work on improving some of the existing websites designed by the company.
- I collaborate with back-end developers and product designers, monitor website traffic and troubleshoot website problems as they arise.
- I carry out other administrative tasks including typing, content creation and record-keeping. Technology Used: WordPress, Divi, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript, React.

## **HIACE SYSTEM LIMITED, Ibadan 2016-2019** Intern

- Built analytical solution to solve some of the problems with employee and customer data to get valuable insight, for better decision making.
- Analyzing data using statistical techniques and providing reports.
- Served as an instructor for students (disabled) on the basics of web development during google code week 2018.
- Developing and implementing databases and data collection systems.
- Technology Used: Python, Tableau, Google Analytics.

## **CREATIVE MINDS, University of Ibadan 2019 – 2020** Tutor

- Implementing real world scenarios into computer programming in order to facilitate the learning of the learners.
- Taught newbie developers' basics of programming and web design.

Technology Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git and GitHub.

## **PROJECTS:**

## **Ar-Rifaha Digital Cooperative**

It is a Web App that allow users carry out all co-operative activities like savings, loan application and repayment, record keeping, shopping and so on.

### **Technology Used:**

• PHP • MySQL

JavascriptPaystack API

Git and Github
Google Material design

### **Activities**

Created contents for the website. • Modified parts of the front-end.

• Had major decision on the architecture and functioning of the project. • Tested and debugged application

**Project Link** 

# **EDUCATION**

\_\_\_\_\_

2014 – 2021 Bsc (Engr) in Agricultural and Environmental Engineering, University of Ibadan, Ibadan.

2008 – 2014 West African School Senior Certificate Examination (WASSCE), Command Day Secondary School, Odogbo, Ibadan.

**REFERENCES:** Available on Request